<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Medical on Home</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/categories/medical/</link><description>Recent content in Medical on Home</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zhilinggavin.github.io/categories/medical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Publication Projects</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/publication/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/publication/</guid><description>Exploring projects resulted in publciation</description></item><item><title>DiffSeg: Diffusion-Based Weakly Supervised Segmentation for Fibrosis</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/diffusion-wsss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/diffusion-wsss/</guid><description>Figure 1. Pulmonary fibrosis illustartion. Fibrosis can cause irreversible lung damage and is associated with increased mortality. Publication &amp;amp; Presentation This project was published at IEEE ISBI 2025 and featured as an invited presentation in April 2025, Houston, TX, USA.
Introduction Fibrotic Lung Disease (FLD) is a life-threatening condition characterised by progressive lung scarring, responsible for 1% of UK deaths in 2021. However, fibrosis appears in irregular and diffuse patterns with poorly defined boundaries, making manual segmentation highly variable and labor-intensive.</description></item><item><title>Auto Lung Anatomy Segmentation</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/auto-lung-segmentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/auto-lung-segmentation/</guid><description>Automatic Lung segmentation Introduction The automatic segmentation of the lung region in chest X-rays (CXR) aids doctors in diagnosing various lung diseases. However, severe lung deformities and indistinct lung boundaries caused by serious conditions can lead to errors in the segmentation model.
Data and task description Dataset consists of collected from public available chest X-Ray (CXR) images. Overall amount of images is 800 meanwhile labeled only 704 of them. Whole dataset was randomly divided into train (0.</description></item><item><title>Explainable AI - Controlable Image Generation</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/explanable-ai/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/explanable-ai/</guid><description>Introduction This project investigates semantic disentanglement techniques to analyse the intermediate latent spaces in generative AI models, such as StyleGAN and Diffusion models. By isolating and utilising these disentangled features, we aim to develop prognostic models for lung diseases that are more interpretable for clinicians and researchers. This approach will facilitate the identification of novel biomarkers for lung disease prognosis. The detailed project in medical domain can be found in the poster.</description></item><item><title>MRI Reconstruction Artefacts: Simulation &amp; Mitigation Strategies</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/mri-reconstruction/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/mri-reconstruction/</guid><description>A technical exploration of &lt;strong>MRI reconstruction degradation&lt;/strong> caused by &lt;strong>k-space&lt;/strong> sampling errors and patient motion, with clinically informed mitigation strategies.</description></item><item><title>Stereo 3D Reconstruction | Volume Visualisation</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/3d-scene-reconstruction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/3d-scene-reconstruction/</guid><description>Project Description As part of the Image-Guided Intervention module at Imperial College London, this project explored core computer vision methods for 3D scene understanding in medical applications. It combined stereo image analysis, geometric reasoning, and volumetric visualisation using real clinical and biological datasets.
Figure: Example stereo images from a video sequence, used for 3D scene reconstruction 🧠 Project Highlights 🔹 Epipolar Geometry &amp;amp; Tracking Analysed camera motion and depth perception under pure translation scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Robotic Arms | Trajectory Plan</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/robotic-arm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/robotic-arm/</guid><description>Project Introduction This project involves robotic modelling based on a real 6-DOF robotic arm. The robotic arm&amp;rsquo;s path planning and control were simulated and validated using MATLAB and CoppeliaSim.
The final evaluation was based on real-world performance during the Live Demonstration, where the project successfully achieved an 80% grade.
Assessment - Live Demonstration Task 1: Grab and Place Objective: Pick up a cube and accurately place it in a specified spot with a maximum error of 1mm.</description></item><item><title>Hyperspectral Imaging – Optical Modelling for Histological Image Segmentation</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/hsi-absorption/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/hsi-absorption/</guid><description>Simulating &lt;strong>hyperspectral absorption&lt;/strong> in MATLAB for label-free &lt;strong>tissue segmentation&lt;/strong> using &lt;strong>haemoglobin spectral&lt;/strong> properties</description></item><item><title>Medical Image Analysis - Vessel Segmentation and Filtering</title><link>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/medical-image-analysis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://zhilinggavin.github.io/project/medical-image-analysis/</guid><description>This project, completed as part of the Image-Guided Intervention module at Imperial College London, explores classical image processing techniques for analyzing retinal images from the DRIVE dataset. The goal is to detect and segment blood vessels using low-level computer vision methods without relying on deep learning.
Figure: Retinal image used for vessel segmentation
### 🧠 Key Tasks &amp; Techniques 1. Edge Detection
Various 3×3 kernels were implemented to detect horizontal, vertical, and diagonal lines.</description></item></channel></rss>